我们的下一个启发是快速失败，
Our next heuristic is failing fast,
也就是说代码应该显示
which means the code should reveal
它的虫子越早越好。
its bugs as early as possible.
我们越早发现有虫子，
The earlier we find out there's a bug,
越接近代码中的实际原因，
the closer to its actual cause in the code,
越容易找到和修复。
the easier it's going to find and fix.
我们在一读时看到了这种区别
We saw in the first reading this distinction
在静态检查和动态检查之间
between static checking and dynamic checking
不检查。
and no checking.
这与快速失败有关，因为静态检查
And this relates to fail fast, because static checking
是你失败的最快速度。
is as fast as you can fail.
在运行代码之前，你会发现这个bug。
You'll find the bug before you even run the code.
动态检查稍晚
Dynamic checking is a little bit later
最糟糕的是节点检查，
and node checking is worst of all,
因为这意味着你要
because it means that you're going
产生一个错误的答案
to produce a wrong answer that's going
破坏后续计算。
to corrupt subsequent computation.
你可能要做很多调试才能真正发现
And you may have to do a lot of debugging to actually find out
虫子在哪里。
where the bug is.
所以快速失败是非常非常重要的。
So fail fast is really, really important.
我给你举的例子不会很快失败。
Our example I gave your method doesn't fail fast.
如果你的论点不对，
If you give it the wrong arguments,
很容易把这些论点放错顺序，
and it's very easy to put these arguments in the wrong order,
例如，Java静态检查
for example, Java static checking
不会帮你的，因为这些都是智力。
isn't going to help you because all of these are ints.
所以Java不在乎这些顺序是否错误。
So Java doesn't care that these are in the wrong order.
里面的代码没有做任何动态检查
And the code inside it isn't doing any dynamic checking
或者，为了确保这个月
either, even to make sure that the month
一个月中的哪一天在合理的范围内。
and the day of the month are in reasonable ranges.
它只是继续计算一些答案，如果你
It just goes ahead and computes some answer, which if you
把论点放错顺序，
put the arguments in the wrong order,
会是错误的答案。
would be the wrong answer.
事实上，设计的方式，
And in fact, the way this is designed,
它实际上假设月、日和年
it's actually assuming that the month, day, and year are
在美国的秩序中
in the American order, whereas most of the rest of the world
不是把月放在第一位，而是把它放在中间。
doesn't put the month first, but instead puts it in the middle.
一天，一个月，一年，或者一年，一个月，一天。
Either day, month, year or year, month, day.
所以这个函数，为了写得好，
So this function, in order to be well written,
实际上需要更多的检查，
actually needs a lot more checking,
使用类型进行静态检查或动态检查。
either static checking using types or dynamic checking.